<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<help>
<sect name="Getting Started" sid="1">
<Subsect name="Choose your Character" ssid="1">
<q qid="1">
<qTxt>What do I do here?</qTxt>
<aTxt>This is where you create the character that you will control in GalaXseeds! You can change five different parts of your character: the head, the legs, the body, the left arm and the right arm. You can also customize the colour of each part.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="2">
<qTxt>How do I change body parts?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click on the arrow buttons next to each of the body part names.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="3">
<qTxt>How do I colour a body part?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click on the name of the body part.  Then, click anywhere in the colour box.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="4">
<qTxt>What does the random button do?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click 'Random' to let the game create a character for you. You can click this button as many times as you like. If the game chooses something that looks almost perfect, you can always change one or two body parts by clicking the arrow buttons next to each of the body part names.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="5">
<qTxt>Can I change my character later?</qTxt>
<aTxt>As long as you are still in the setup phase, you can go back and change your character. Once you finish the set up phase and are in the game world, you will not be able to make any changes.  So choose wisely!</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="6">
<qTxt>What&apos;s the difference between the characters?  Are some characters better than others?</qTxt>
<aTxt>All the characters have the exact same abilities - no body parts are better than others. The only difference is that each character has its own Grooves (e.g. dance moves), but these don&apos;t affect the way you play the game.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="7">
<qTxt>I clicked &apos;Next&apos; when I wasn&apos;t finished! How do I go back?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click the 'Back' button. You can change your character as long as you are still in the setup phase of GalaXseeds.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="8">
<qTxt>What do I do when I&apos;m finished building my character?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click the 'Next' button to go to the next section.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
</Subsect><Subsect name="Choose your Clan" ssid="2">
<q qid="1">
<qTxt>What do I do here?</qTxt>
<aTxt>This screen is where you decide on your home planet.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="2">
<qTxt>What&apos;s a Clan?</qTxt>
<aTxt>GalaXseeds is made up of four planets. Each planet is very different. When you choose a home planet, you become a member of that planet&apos;s Clan. Clans are like teams. You&apos;ll have to work together with the rest of your team to score points and win challenges.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="3">
<qTxt>What&apos;s the difference between the Clans?  Which is the best Clan?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Each Clan planet looks very different, and the maps are all laid out differently.  Choosing a Clan is all about deciding which planet you think looks the best, so don&apos;t be too worried about making the wrong decision!</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="4">
<qTxt>Will the Clan with the most people win all the challenges and score the most points?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Points are scored based on an average of how many people are in each of the Clans, so there is no advantage to being in a Clan that has more members.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="5">
<qTxt>How do I see information for the other Clans?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click the arrow buttons to cycle through descriptions for each Clan planet.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="6">
<qTxt>Can I change my Clan later?</qTxt>
<aTxt>As long as you are in the setup phase of GalaXseeds, you can change your Clan.  Once you are in the game world, you become a permanent member of your chosen Clan, so choose wisely!</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="7">
<qTxt>I&apos;ve picked the Clan I like. Now what?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click the 'Next' button to move to the next section of the setup phase.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
</Subsect><Subsect name="Choose your Pod" ssid="3">
<q qid="1">
<qTxt>What do I do here?</qTxt>
<aTxt>This screen is where you customize the outside of your Pod. You can pick the pattern and the colour you want it to be.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="2">
<qTxt>What&apos;s a Pod?</qTxt>
<aTxt>A Pod is where you live on GalaXseeds. It&apos;s a hinged capsule that folds open. Pods are split into two halves.  On one side is your living space, and on the other side is your garden.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="3">
<qTxt>Can I customize my living space and garden?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Yes!  That happens after you complete the setup phase and start playing the game. You will be able to add Gear (e.g. furniture) and grow Plants.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="4">
<qTxt>How do I put a pattern on my Pod?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click on the arrow buttons to choose a different pattern for your Pod.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="6">
<qTxt>How do I colour my Pod?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click anywhere in the colour box to choose a colour for your Pod.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="6">
<qTxt>What&apos;s the best colour or pattern?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Colours and patterns have no effect on gameplay - so pick whatever you like best!</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="5">
<qTxt>Are these the only patterns I can choose from?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Yes.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="8">
<qTxt>Can I change the colour and pattern of my Pod later on?</qTxt>
<aTxt>As long as you are still in the setup phase, you can change the colour and pattern of your Pod. Once you have entered the game world, you will not be able to change them.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="9">
<qTxt>I&apos;m finished customizing my Pod. Now what?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click on the next button to enter the GalaXseeds game world!</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
</Subsect><Subsect name="Choose your Server" ssid="4">
<q qid="1">
<qTxt>What do I do here?</qTxt>
<aTxt>This screen is where you choose which server you want to join.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="2">
<qTxt>What &apos;s a server?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Each server contains an identical copy of the GalaXseeds world. The game needs to be split up because we can&apos;t fit everyone into one copy! Think of these servers as different copies of the same book.  Everyone might be reading the same story, even if they&apos;re reading different books!</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="3">
<qTxt>Once I choose a server, am I stuck there forever?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Nope! Whenever you start playing the game, you can pick the server you want to play in. You are able to join any server as long as it is not currently full.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="4">
<qTxt>How do I choose a server?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click on the server name to join that server.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="5">
<qTxt>I keep clicking on a server but nothing happens.  What&apos;s going on?</qTxt>
<aTxt>The server you&apos;re trying to join is full.  Try choosing a different server.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="6">
<qTxt>How do I know what server my Friends are playing in?</qTxt>
<aTxt>If any of the players that you have added as friends are currently online, their names will appear in the 'Friendly Seedizens' list. When you roll your cursor over each server, the names of any Seedizens that are in that server will light up.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="7">
<qTxt>Why don't I don't see anyone in the Friendly Seedizen list?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Either none of your Friends are currently online, or you haven't added any players to your Friends list.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="8">
<qTxt>My Friends are scattered across different servers.  How can I play with them all at the same time?</qTxt>
<aTxt>You can try to get your Friends all to meet up on one server. Figure out the server you want to play on, then enter the other servers and send messages to your friends asking them to meet you on that other server.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
</Subsect></sect><sect name="Pods" sid="2">
<Subsect name="Your Pod" ssid="1">
<q qid="1">
<qTxt>What do I do in my Pod?</qTxt>
<aTxt>This is your Pod! Think of it as your home away from home. You can do some decorating, work on your garden, or invite your Friends over.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="2">
<qTxt>How do I enter my Pod?</qTxt>
<aTxt>To go to your Pod, first make sure you are on your home Clan planet. Then make your way to the Apodment Complex (check your Map if you need help locating it). Once you have enter the Apodment Complex, just click 'Go To My Pod' and you will appear in your Pod. When you're ready to leave your Pod, just click on the Exit Ring at the doorway and you will appear back outside.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="3">
<qTxt>How do I visit my garden?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Once you are in your Pod, click on the doorway near the Pod&apos;s hinge to enter your garden.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="4">
<qTxt>How do I exit my Pod?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click on the exit ring at the doorway to leave your Pod.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="5">
<qTxt>How do I decorate my Pod?</qTxt>
<aTxt>You can personalize your Pod by adding Gear (furniture) items. Once you are in you Pod, click the flashing icon that has the image of a chair on the left of your screen. This will open the Gear Up menu and from here you can add, remove or arrange Gear in your Pod.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="6">
<qTxt>What is Gear?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Gear is another word for furniture. You add Gear items to your Pod.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="7">
<qTxt>Where do I get Gear?</qTxt>
<aTxt>You can buy Gear at any Gear shop. You can also earn Gear in special missions, or trade for it with other Seedizens.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="8">
<qTxt>How do I add Gear to my Pod?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Open up the Gear Up menu and click the Add button. Choose a Gear item in your inventory. Choose an angle for your Gear. Finally, click to place your Gear in any open spot in your Pod.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="9">
<qTxt>When I try to Gear Up my Pod, the game tells my I can&apos;t. Why not?</qTxt>
<aTxt>You can only add Gear to your Pod if you have Gear in your inventory. You will need to go buy some Gear at a Gear shop before you can decorate.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="10">
<qTxt>Why can&apos;t I place my Gear wherever I want?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Some spots in your Pod won't accept Gear items. For example, you can't place Gear in front of any exits, and you can&apos;t put certain pieces of Gear on top of each other.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="11">
<qTxt>How do I remove Gear from my Pod?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Open the Gear Up menu and click the 'Take Back' button. Then click on the Gear item you want to remove. It will be removed from your Pod and will go into your inventory.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="12">
<qTxt>What happens to the Gear I take back from my Pod? Does it get deleted?</qTxt>
<aTxt>No. Any Gear that you take back is placed in your inventory.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="13">
<qTxt>How do I rearrange the Gear in my Pod?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Open up the Gear Up menu and click the 'Move' button. Then click on the Gear you want to move, and then click on a new spot to place it. You can also change the angle of a Gear item by click the 'Rotate' button and then clicking on the item.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="14">
<qTxt>Why can&apos;t I put the Gear item back in the same spot after rotating it?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Your Gear item might make a different footprint in your Pod after it&apos;s been rotated. You&apos;ll have to pick a different place in your Pod to put it.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="15">
<qTxt>How do I add Gear to my garden?</qTxt>
<aTxt>You can only add Gear to the living space in your Pod. Your garden is reserved for Plants.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="16">
<qTxt>I know I own a Gear item, why can&apos;t I find it in my inventory?</qTxt>
<aTxt>When you place Gear items in your Pod, they&apos; are removed from your inventory. You have to remove an item from your Pod if you want to trade, sell, or view it in your inventory.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="17">
<qTxt>Someone&apos;s in my Pod! How did that happen?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Once you are logged in to GalaXseeds, any other Seedizen can visit your Pod.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="18">
<qTxt>Can visitors mess with my Gear?</qTxt>
<aTxt>No - your Gear is safe. Visitors can only admire it.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="19">
<qTxt>Why can&apos;t I Gear Up my Pod when I have visitors?</qTxt>
<aTxt>We don&apos;t want you dropping a subofa on your Friends! Asking your visitors to leave is safer for everyone. You can invite everyone back when you&apos;re finished decorating.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
</Subsect><Subsect name="Your Garden" ssid="2">
<q qid="1">
<qTxt>What do I do in my garden?</qTxt>
<aTxt>This is your own private garden where you plant Seeds and care for your Plants. You can also invite your Friends over to see your latest creations.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="4">
<qTxt>What are those brown lumpy squares?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Those are dirt pits. You can plant Seeds in them and grow new Plants.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="5">
<qTxt>How do I get more pits?</qTxt>
<aTxt>All Pods are limited to five planting pits.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="6">
<qTxt>How do I plant a Seed?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Make sure you have a Seed in your inventory. To plant it, just click on one of your empty pits.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="7">
<qTxt>Where do I get Seeds?</qTxt>
<aTxt>You can buy Seeds from the Garden Shop or get them through trading. You can also get them from Plants you successfully grow to maturity (when a Plant reaches maturity it drops Seeds).</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="8">
<qTxt>The game won&apos;t let me plant a Seed.  Why not?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Either all of your pits are full, or you don&apos;t have any Seeds to plant.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="9">
<qTxt>How do I check to see how one of my Plants is doing?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click on a plant to bring up its Click on the Plant to bring up the Plant management screen. From this screen you can check out its Health and Lifespan stats, as well as care for it.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="10">
<qTxt>My Plant grew huge all of a sudden! What's going on?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Your Plant reached the next level of its lifespan. There are 5 lifespans in total.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="11">
<qTxt>My Plant is all brown and withered. What happened?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Your Plant has moved on to that Great Greenhouse in the Sky!  Dead plants take up room in your garden, and they look pretty ugly, so you should remove them.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="12">
<qTxt>How do I remove a dead Plant?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click on the dead Plant and then choose the 'Pull' option to pull it out.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="14">
<qTxt>Someone&apos;s in my Garden!</qTxt>
<aTxt>When you are logged in to GalaXseeds, any other Seedizen can visit your garden to check out your Plants.</aTxt>
<img></img>
<link1 sID="2" ssID="5" qID="9">See this section</link1>
</q>
<q qid="15">
<qTxt>Can visitors mess with my Plants?</qTxt>
<aTxt>No - your Plants are safe.  Visitors can only admire them.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="2">
<qTxt>How do I exit my Pod?</qTxt>
<aTxt>You exit your Pod through the living space side. You cannot exit from your garden.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="3">
<qTxt>How do I get to my living space?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click on the exit arrow to leave your garden and go to the living space side of your Pod.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
</Subsect><Subsect name="Visiting Pods" ssid="3">
<q qid="1">
<qTxt>How do I visit another player's Pod?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Enter the Apodment Complex and click on the name of the player whose Pod you want to check out. Then hit 'Visit'.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="2">
<qTxt>What can I do in a player's Pod?</qTxt>
<aTxt>You can hang out and admire their Gear, or visit their garden and see their Plants. You can also chat or trade with anyone else in the Pod.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="3">
<qTxt>How do I exit their Pod?</qTxt>
<aTxt>If you are in the garden, click on the exit arrow to enter the living space.  From the living space, click on the exit ring to return to the Apodment Complex.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="4">
<qTxt>Can I take this player&apos;s stuff?</qTxt>
<aTxt>No.  That wouldn&apos;t be very nice.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="5">
<qTxt>Can I take care of this player&apos;s Plants?</qTxt>
<aTxt>No. Plants are the responsibility of the garden owner.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="6">
<qTxt>Where did the player get this stuff?  Why haven&apos;t I ever seen it?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Some players might have Gear items that were earned through special missions, or in exclusive store sales. Different items are always coming and going so make sure to check the shops often!  Many of the Plants you see in GalaXseeds are the result of experimentation. By combining two Seeds in the same pit, players can create an endless variety of Plants!</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="7">
<qTxt>How do I trade the Pod owner for their Gear items?</qTxt>
<aTxt>You&apos;ll have to ask the owner nicely if he or she wants to trade. [link to trading section]</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="8">
<qTxt>Where is the Pod owner?</qTxt>
<aTxt>If you don't see the owner in the Pod, it means he/she is somewhere out in the world. You can check the Seedizen list to see if they are somewhere nearby.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="9">
<qTxt>Why did the Pod owner ask me to leave the Pod?  Did I do something wrong?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Maybe they want some time alone! But more likely, the owner just wanted to move some Gear around.  You can probably come back once the owner is finished.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
</Subsect></sect><sect name="General" sid="3">
<Subsect name="General" ssid="1">
<q qid="1">
<qTxt>What do I do here?</qTxt>
<aTxt>This is the GalaXseeds world, where everything happens! There&apos;s so much to do in the game, that it's impossible to sum it all up in one sentence!  Click on the other topics to see all the amazing things you can do!</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="2">
<qTxt>There are lots of people here!  Which character is me?</qTxt>
<aTxt>All of the characters have usernames written beneath them.  If you can&apos;t find your character right away, click somewhere on the screen and watch for a character to walk there. That&apos;s probably you.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="3">
<qTxt>How do I move around?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click somewhere and your character will walk there. To move to the next area, click on the arrow exits that appear on the edges of the screen.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="4">
<qTxt>How do I figure out where to go?</qTxt>
<aTxt>The game world is littered with signposts pointing the way to important places. You can also check out the Map by clicking the Map button in the top right corner of the screen.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="9">
<qTxt>How do I look at the stuff I&apos;m carrying?</qTxt>
<aTxt>That&apos;s called your inventory.  Click on the Inventory button in the top left corner of the screen to see which items you have.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="10">
<qTxt>How do I read the news?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click on the News button in the bottom right corner of the screen.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="11">
<qTxt>Does everyone see the same news?</qTxt>
<aTxt>No. The news can be different depending on where you live or which clan you belong to.  It can even change depending on how experienced a gardener you are.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="5">
<qTxt>How do I look at the Map?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click the icon in the top right corner of the screen. That will bring up the Map of the planet you are on. There is an option to see &apos;Full Map&apos; - which you can click if you want to see the map of all 4 planets.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="6">
<qTxt>What are Teleplanters?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Teleplanters are special travel devices that will teleport you to other places on the planet. You can see where Teleplanters are located by checking out the Map.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="7">
<qTxt>What is all that info along the top of the screen?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Along the top of the screen is all your important Character information. It includes your name, your title, your level, your Experience Points (XP), and how many Botanickels (coins) you have.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="8">
<qTxt>How do I make money?</qTxt>
<aTxt>You earn Botanickels (coins) by playing Mini Games. You can also make money by selling Seeds that you collect from Plants you successfully raise to maturity.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="12">
<qTxt>How do I earn Experience Points (XP)?</qTxt>
<aTxt>You earn Experience Points (XP) by caring for your Plants until they reach maturity. Different Plants give different amounts of XP. For instance, more complex Plants will give more XP. Plants grown from grafted (combined) Seeds usually give higher XP as well.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
</Subsect><Subsect name="Options" ssid="2">
<q qid="1">
<qTxt>What do I do here?</qTxt>
<aTxt>The Options screen lets you tune the game according to your preferences.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="2">
<qTxt>What&apos;s the deal with the Quality setting?</qTxt>
<aTxt>On some computers, the game will run faster if you choose the lowest Quality setting, but it won&apos;t look as nice.  If the game performs very slowly, try choosing a lower Quality setting to see if it makes a difference.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="3">
<qTxt>What&apos;s with the Social options?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Choose &quot;Block Trades from strangers&quot; or &quot;Block Whispers from strangers&quot; to make sure that you only see Whispers and trade requests from players you have added to your Friendly Seedizens list.  These are like &quot;Do not disturb&quot; settings. You can turn them on and off whenever you like.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="4">
<qTxt>How do I block Trades and Whispers from my Friends?</qTxt>
<aTxt>The game assumes that Trades and Whispers from your Friends are always welcomed. However if one of your Friends is constantly asking you for trades or Whispering to you and it is bothering you, consider removing that person from your Friendly Seedizens list!</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="5">
<qTxt>What&apos;s the deal with GalaXseeds time?</qTxt>
<aTxt>GalaXseeds is played by people around the world, and clocks show different times depending on where you live. If you say &quot;Meet me at the Strataquarium at 7:00&quot;, your friend might be there at a completely different time and you&apos;ll miss each other.  GalaXseeds time is common to all players.  Use it to make sure everyone&apos;s playing by the same clock.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="6">
<qTxt>What does the logoff button do?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click this button to return to the Choose Your Server screen.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="7">
<qTxt>How do I save my game?  Will I lose anything if I click the logoff button?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Your GalaXseeds progress is automatically saved while you play. You won&apos;t lose anything by logging out of the game.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
</Subsect></sect><sect name="Chatting" sid="4">
<Subsect name="Chatting" ssid="1">
<q qid="1">
<qTxt>How do I chat?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click on the chat button (bottom left corner of your screen). Put your mouse over the chat phrases to find one you like. Click on the phrase to make your character say it.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="2">
<qTxt>Why didn&apos;t my character say the chat phrase I clicked on?</qTxt>
<aTxt>The phrase probably needs a special [select] word. The phrase builder is waiting for you to choose a word from the dictionary to finish the phrase.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="3">
<qTxt>How do I finish a [select] chat phrase?</qTxt>
<aTxt>You can type the word you want to say and press the Enter key on your keyboard. Or you can choose a word from the GalaXseeds dictionary and then click the Send button to say the phrase.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="4">
<qTxt>Why does my typing turn red?</qTxt>
<aTxt>If you tried to type a word and it turned red it means that the word isn&apos;t in the GalaXseeds dictionary, so you won&apos;t be able to say it right now.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="6">
<qTxt>Why can&apos;t I say whatever I want?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Because GalaXseeds attracts young gamers, Internet safety is very important to us. The chat system is limited so that players are guaranteed to have a fun, safe game experience.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="13">
<qTxt>How do I make one of those little heads appear above my character?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Those are called Moods. Click on the Emoticons button (bottom left corner of the screen) to see your choice of Moods, and then click on a Mood to display it above your character.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="14">
<qTxt>How do I show my Mood?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click on the Emoticons button (bottom left of screen) to see your list of Moods. Then click on a Mood - that image will appear above your character&apos;s head.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="15">
<qTxt>How do I show my Grooves?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click the Special Move button to see your list of Grooves, and then click on one to make your character show off.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="16">
<qTxt>Why do my Get-ups disappear when my character grooves?</qTxt>
<aTxt>When your character has an action to perform, sometimes Get-ups get in the way!  Don't worry - they'll come back as soon as you're finished showing off.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="17">
<qTxt>What do the symbols above players&apos; heads mean?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Some of these symbols may be Moods, which are ways that a player can show how he or she is feeling.  Other symbols might show what the player is doing (e.g. trading).</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="6">
<qTxt>What is Whispering?</qTxt>
<aTxt>When you chat, the things you say are shown to everyone in the room. If you Whisper something to someone, your chat phrases only will be seen by that person. Whispering is a great way to send out an invitation without the whole world knowing about it!</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="7">
<qTxt>How do I whisper?</qTxt>
<aTxt>To send a Whisper to someone, you can double-click on the player and click &quot;Whisper&quot;. Or you can choose someone from the Seedizens List and click &quot;Whisper&quot;.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="8">
<qTxt>Someone is whispering to me - what do I do?</qTxt>
<aTxt>You can click the &quot;REPLY&quot; button to Whisper message to send one back to that player. If you don't want to reply, just click the Whisper icon in the bottom left corner close the Whisper Log.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="9">
<qTxt>Another player keeps sending me whispers and it's getting annoying - what do I do?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Double-click on the player&apos;s character, or point to the player in the Seedizen List, and click &quot;Ignore&quot;.  You won&apos;t receive Whispers from players you are ignoring.  You can also click the Options button (lower right of screen) and select &quot;Block Whispers from strangers&quot; to only see Whispers from players on your Friendly Seedizens list.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="10">
<qTxt>The Whisper Log disappeared - how do I get it back?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click the Whisper Log icon (bottom left corner of screen) to open and close the Whisper Log.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="11">
<qTxt>How do I close the Whisper Log?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click the Whisper Log icon (bottom left corner of screen) to open and close the Whisper Log.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="12">
<qTxt>How do I whisper to someone in a different area?</qTxt>
<aTxt>You can send a Whisper to people on your Friendly Seedizens List, even when your friends are in different areas - or on different planets! Just click on their name in the Seedizens List and choose the 'Whisper' option.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
</Subsect></sect><sect name="Trading" sid="5">
<Subsect name="Trading" ssid="1">
<q qid="1">
<qTxt>How do I ask someone to trade with me?</qTxt>
<aTxt>If you are standing in the same area as the player you want to trade with, double-click on their character and choose 'Trade' from the option list. You can also click on someone's name in the Seedizens List to trade. The other player has the option to either accept or deny your trade request.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="2">
<qTxt>How does trading work?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Ask someone to trade with you and then wait for them to accept. When they do, an Accept message will appear. A Trade Block will appear in the centre of your screen along with a Fair Trade Meter. Click on the item(s) in your inventory you would like to trade. Then click on the item(s) in the other person&apos;s inventory that you would like. The Fair Trade Meter shows how 'fair' (even) the trade is. Click on the &apos;Trade&apos; button. The other player can then accept your offers or change the items up for grab. Once you are both happy, the trade will occur.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="4">
<qTxt>How do I check out another player's inventory screen?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click on a player and then choose the 'Inventory' option. The inventory screen shows what items the player is carrying.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="3">
<qTxt>What is the Fair Trade Meter?</qTxt>
<aTxt>The Fair Trade Meter lets you know if the items being traded are worth a similar value. When the arrow points to 'green' the offer is fair.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="5">
<qTxt>Someone asked me if I want to trade. What do I do?</qTxt>
<aTxt>If you want to trade with that player, you can 'Accept' their request. If you don't want to trade, just say no to their request.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
</Subsect></sect><sect name="Seedizens" sid="6">
<Subsect name="Seedizens" ssid="1">
<q qid="1">
<qTxt>How do I see who's in this area?</qTxt>
<aTxt>If things are getting crowded, you can open the Seedizens List to see all of the people in the room. Click the Seedizens List button, and then click the Nearby Seedizens section if it's not already open.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="2">
<qTxt>How can I tell who is currently online?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Open up the Seedizen List. Everyone listed in the Nearby Seedizens section is online. Friendly Seedizens' names will be dark if they are online, and faded if they are offline.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="3">
<qTxt>What are Nearby Seedizens?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Nearby Seedizens are players who are in the same area as you.  Once you leave the area, or as players come and go, this list will change. Click the Seedizens List button, and then click the Nearby Seedizens section to see who is in your area.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="4">
<qTxt>I saw someone a few seconds ago who isn't in my Nearby Seedizens section.  What's up with that?</qTxt>
<aTxt>The Nearby Seedizens section changes as players come and go, and as you move around GalaXseeds.  If you can see someone in the same area as you who is not in the Nearby Seedizens section of the Seedizens List, the list has probably not refreshed itself.  Close and then re-open the Seedizens List to refresh it.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="5">
<qTxt>What's a Friendly Seedizen?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Friendly Seedizens are those players you have added as Friends. Adding people to your Friendly Seedizens list lets you keep track of who you enjoy playing the game with.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="6">
<qTxt>How do I make Friends?</qTxt>
<aTxt>To keep track of someone you enjoy playing GalaXseeds with, click on that person's character, and then click the 'Add Friend' option.  You can also make a Friend by pointing to someone's name in the Seedizens List and clicking 'Add Friend'.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="7">
<qTxt>What's the point of having Friends?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Normally, you can only whisper or trade with people who are in the same area as you.  Friends can whisper and trade with each other even when they're in different areas. Making Friends is the best way to enjoy the game!</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="8">
<qTxt>Why are some of my Friends' names faded?</qTxt>
<aTxt>The faded Friends are not online, which means they are not playing GalaXseeds right now.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="9">
<qTxt>How do I remove someone from my Friends list?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Open the Seedizens List and point to your Friend's name. Click on 'Remove Friend' to remove the player from your list. You can also click the player's character and choose the 'Remove Friend' option.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="10">
<qTxt>What if I don't want to be on someone's Friends list?</qTxt>
<aTxt>If someone is pestering you, you can add that person to your Ignored Seedizens list.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="11">
<qTxt>I keep trying to whisper or trade with someone, but there's no response.  What's going on?</qTxt>
<aTxt>The person you're trying to contact is either busy, or ignoring you.  Players might add you to their Ignore section if they feel you are being a pest, or if they simply want some privacy.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="12">
<qTxt>How do I convince someone to take me off their Ignore list?</qTxt>
<aTxt>If you are on a player's Ignore list, there's nothing you can do about it.  You should respect that player's privacy and find other friendly Seedizens to play with.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="13">
<qTxt>Another player keeps bugging me.  How do I ignore them?</qTxt>
<aTxt>If you really don't want to hear from certain people, you can add them to your Ignored Seedizens list.  To do this, click on the player you want to ignore, and then click the 'Ignore Player' option from the flyout menu. You can also ignore a player by clicking on their name in the Seedizen List and then choosing 'Ignore'.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="14">
<qTxt>How do I ignore a player?</qTxt>
<aTxt>If you really don't want to hear from certain people, you can add them to your Ignored Seedizens list.  To do this, click on the player you want to ignore, and then click the 'Ignore Player' option from the flyout menu. You can also ignore a player by clicking on their name in the Seedizen List and then choosing 'Ignore'.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="15">
<qTxt>How do I stop ignoring a player?</qTxt>
<aTxt>To remove someone from your Ignored list, open the Seedizens List. Point to the ignored player's name and click 'Stop Ignoring'. If the player is in your area, you can also click their character and choose 'Stop Ignoring' from the menu flyout.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="16">
<qTxt>How do I look at another player's inventory?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Open the Seedizens List, point to a player and choose 'Inventory'. You can also double-click on a player's character and choose 'Inventory' from the menu flyout.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="20">
<qTxt>Can I dress another player, or spend another player's Experience Points (XP)?</qTxt>
<aTxt>No!</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="18">
<qTxt>Can I take any of the player's items?</qTxt>
<aTxt>No!  But you can ask this player for a trade.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="19">
<qTxt>How do I ask a player for a trade?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Double-click on the character you want to trade with and then choose the 'Trade' option to send the request. The other player can then either accept or reject it your request.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="17">
<qTxt>How do I see what Level another player is or what title they have?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Double-click on a player to bring up their inventory window. From here you can see their character info including their Level and title. You can also see how many Botanickels they have.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
</Subsect></sect><sect name="Inventory / Profile" sid="7">
<Subsect name="Inventory / Profile" ssid="1">
<q qid="1">
<qTxt>What is the inventory screen?</qTxt>
<aTxt>The inventory screen shows everything you're carrying as well as your character info. It is also where you go when it's time to level up.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="2">
<qTxt>How do I look at my stuff?</qTxt>
<aTxt>To look at your inventory, click the 'Inventory' icon in the top left corner of the screen. This will bring up the inventory screen. The screen is split into sections (e.g. Get-ups, Seeds), and clicking on the tabs will let you see the items you have in each group.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="3">
<qTxt>How do I carry more stuff?</qTxt>
<aTxt>More experienced gardeners are able to carry more items.  Keep growing plants and completing missions to raise your level and increase your Inventory size.</aTxt>
<img></img>
<link1 sID="7" ssID="15" qID="14">Levelling</link1>
</q>
<q qid="4">
<qTxt>I bought some Gear and placed it in my Pod, but it's not in my inventory. Where did it go?</qTxt>
<aTxt>When you Gear Up your Pod, your Gear is removed from your Inventory.  When you are in your Pod, you can use the Take Back button to put your Gear back in your Inventory.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="5">
<qTxt>How do I wear a Get-up?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click on the Get-ups tab in the inventory window to look at your Get-ups. Click on the Get-up item you want to wear and it will appear on your character.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="6">
<qTxt>How do I take off a Get-up?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click on the Get-ups tab in the inventory window to look at your Get-ups. Click on the Get-up you are wearing and it will be removed from your character.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="7">
<qTxt>Why is my first Get-up removed when I try to wear a second Get-up?</qTxt>
<aTxt>You can only wear one Get-up on one part of your body. For example, you can't wear two hats at the same time, but you can wear a hat and a tie together since they are worn on different parts of your body.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="8">
<qTxt>What is the word beneath my player name?</qTxt>
<aTxt>That's your title. You earn different titles by Leveling Up your character.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="9">
<qTxt>What can I do with my title?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Your title is just a way of showing everyone what an amazing player you are.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="10">
<qTxt>How do I get a different title?</qTxt>
<aTxt>You'll receive a new title every five levels. Level Up your character to keep earning new titles and rewards.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="11">
<qTxt>What are the numbers beneath my player name?</qTxt>
<aTxt>That number shows your wealth on The Big Rip. When you play GalaXseeds, your Creds are turned into Botanickels. If you play a different game on The Big Rip, your Creds are converted into that game's currency.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="13">
<qTxt>Can I spend Botanickels in other games on The Big Rip?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Yes!  The Big Rip money is called Creds. Your Creds are the same whether you are playing GalaXseeds or any other game on The Big Rip.  If you have 500 Creds, they become 500 Botanickels in GalaXseeds.  When you enter a different game, your money and Experience Points (XP) go with you.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="13">
<qTxt>What are the numbers beneath my character picture?</qTxt>
<aTxt>These numbers show your current Experience Points (XP), and the cost of Leveling Up your character.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="14">
<qTxt>How do I Level Up?</qTxt>
<aTxt>If you have earned enough Experience Points (XP) to Level Up, the Level Up button in your Inventory Window will be activated.  Click the Level Up button to move your character to the next experience level.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="15">
<qTxt>How do I earn Experience Points (XP)?</qTxt>
<aTxt>You earn Experience Points (XP) by caring for your Plants until they reach maturity. Different Plants give different amounts of XP. For instance, more complex Plants will give more XP. Plants grown from grafted (combined) Seeds usually give higher XP as well.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="16">
<qTxt>What if I have enough Experience Points (XP) to level up more than once?</qTxt>
<aTxt>The Level Up button will stay active as long as you have enough Experience Points (XP) to reach the next level.  You can keep clicking the Level Up button to Level Up your character if you have enough Experience Points (XP) to do so.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="17">
<qTxt>Can I use my Experience Points (XP) in other games on The Big Rip?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Yes!  Your Experience Points and money travel with you to other games in The Big Rip system.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="18">
<qTxt>I Leveled Up my character in a different game on The Big Rip, and I lost  Experience Points (XP) in GalaXseeds.  What happened?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Your Experience Points (XP) are the same across all games on The Big Rip.  If you spend your points to gain levels in other games on The Big Rip, you'll have fewer points to use in GalaXseeds.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="19">
<qTxt>Can I sell my level to get Experience Points (XP)?</qTxt>
<aTxt>No. Once you have Leveled Up your character it is permanent.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="12">
<qTxt>How do I make money (Botanickels)?</qTxt>
<aTxt>You earn Botanickels by playing mini-games. You can also make money by selling items - like Seeds that get dropped from plants you successfully grow to maturity!</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
</Subsect></sect><sect name="Shopping" sid="8">
<Subsect name="Shopping" ssid="1">
<q qid="1">
<qTxt>Where do I buy items?</qTxt>
<aTxt>There are stores on each of the worlds where you go to buy items. Different shops have different things to buy. You can also sell things back to the shop at a loss.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="3">
<qTxt>I&apos;m in a shop. What's all the stuff on the screen?</qTxt>
<aTxt>The left side of the shop shows the items you have in your inventory. On the right side, you'll see the shopkeeper and the items you can buy.  In the middle is the shopping cart, where you place the items you want to buy or sell.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="11">
<qTxt>What's Gear?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Gear is furniture and stuff you can place in your Pod. You buy it at the Gear shop.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="12">
<qTxt>What are Get-ups?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Get-ups are items you can wear. You buy them at the Get-ups shop.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="13">
<qTxt>What are Gizmos?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Gizmos are special tools that you can use in your garden. You buy them from the Garden shop.</aTxt>
<img>http://www.galaxseeds.com/help/img/gizmos.gif</img>
</q>
<q qid="14">
<qTxt>What are Seeds?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Just like in real life, you use Seeds to grow your own Plants. You buy Seeds from the Garden shop.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="22">
<qTxt>What is the Workshop?</qTxt>
<aTxt>The Workshop is where you go to change the colour of an item. Once you're in the Workshop, click on the item you want to paint from your inventory and then click on the colour of paint can you want to make it. Painting an item costs money.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="6">
<qTxt>How do I know what items cost?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Each item in the shops have a price listed beneath it.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="8">
<qTxt>How do I find out more about an item?</qTxt>
<aTxt>If you want to know more about an item before you buy it, just point your cursor to it to.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="9">
<qTxt>What does the level on an item card mean?</qTxt>
<aTxt>This is the experience level required to use the item. You can buy any item in the game, but you can only use an item if you are the right level.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="7">
<qTxt>How much money do I have?</qTxt>
<aTxt>The number of Botanickels you have is shown along the top of the screen. Or you can open up your inventory and see the amount there.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="4">
<qTxt>How do I buy something?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Enter a stop and click on the item(s) that you want to buy. It will be added to the shopping cart.  You can add up to three items to your cart.  When you are finished, click the &apos;Buy&apos; button to purchase the items</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="5">
<qTxt>Why can't I buy stuff?</qTxt>
<aTxt>There are three reasons why you might not be able to buy what you want. You don't have an empty spot in your inventory screen. You can't afford the items in your shopping cart. Or the store is out of an item.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="15">
<qTxt>How do I sell something?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Go into a shop, and then click on an item in your inventory that you want to sell. The item will be added to your shopping cart. You can sell up to three items at a time.  When you are finished, click the &apos;Sell&apos; button. The item will be removed from your inventory and you will receive the amount of Botanickels the shop offered to pay for it.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="16">
<qTxt>Why does the value of an item go down when I try to sell it?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Just like in the real world, shops buy used items at a reduced price.  If you don't think you're getting good value by selling your items to a shop, try trading your items with other players instead.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="17">
<qTxt>Why can&apos;t I sell or buy any type of item in any type of store?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Different shops deal in different items.  You wouldn&apos;t expect to buy a sofa at a clothing shop.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="18">
<qTxt>Where did the rest of my inventory go?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Don&apos;t worry - you haven&apos;t lost anything. Different shops deal in different items.  Your inventory only shows the type of items that can be bought and sold in this shop.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="19">
<qTxt>Do all shops of the same type sell the same items?</qTxt>
<aTxt>No. For example, the Gear shop on one planet may sell different items than the Gear shop on a different planet.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="20">
<qTxt>Why can&apos;t I find the same items here as I did yesterday?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Shops stock different items at different times.  If you see an item in a shop one day, it might not be there tomorrow!  Items may also be limited in quantity.  If you see an item that you really, really want, you should work very hard to buy it.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="21">
<qTxt>Why is this item a different price than the last time I saw it?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Shop prices are subject to change at any time without warning!</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="2">
<qTxt>Where are the shops?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Check out the map - all the shops are located on it.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
</Subsect></sect><sect name="Mini Games" sid="9">
<Subsect name="Game Lobby" ssid="1">
<q qid="1">
<qTxt>How do I play a Mini Game?</qTxt>
<aTxt>There are Mini Games located in each world. You can find them by checking your Map. If there is a game you want to play, click on the icon and you will enter the game lobby.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="2">
<qTxt>What is the game lobby?</qTxt>
<aTxt>It is the screen where you can join a multiplayer game.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="3">
<qTxt>What do the boxes in the lobby mean?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Those are different game sessions you can join.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="4">
<qTxt>How do I join a game?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click the &apos;Join&apos; button to jump into a game session.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="5">
<qTxt>I joined a game.  Why isn&apos;t anything happening?</qTxt>
<aTxt>You have to wait until the game session fills up with other players. Then the game will begin.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="6">
<qTxt>Can I leave the game session before the game starts?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Yes. Click on the Leave button to leave the session.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="7">
<qTxt>How do I leave a game session?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click on the Leave button to leave the session.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="8">
<qTxt>Why do I see other players in the boxes?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Those are other players waiting to play the game!  Click the Join button to play against them.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="9">
<qTxt>Why did the game session I wanted to join disappear?</qTxt>
<aTxt>As soon as game sessions fill up, they disappear and people start playing the game.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="10">
<qTxt>How do I play against my friend when anyone can join a session?</qTxt>
<aTxt>If you&apos;re waiting to play against someone and a different person joins your session, you&apos;ll have a few seconds to click the Leave button before the game begins.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="11">
<qTxt>My friend started playing a game without me!  Can I join that game?</qTxt>
<aTxt>No. Once a game starts, you&apos;ll have to wait for your friend to finish.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="1">
<qTxt>How do I play a Mini Game?</qTxt>
<aTxt>There are different mini games located around the world. You can find them by checking your Map. Most of these are multi-players games. Playing the mini games are not only fun - but it is also how you earn Coins and XP (Experience Points). . If there is a game you want to play, click on the icon and you will enter it.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="2">
<qTxt>What is the game lobby?</qTxt>
<aTxt>When you enter a multiplayer mini game, you are taken to a screen called the game lobby. This is where you pick the person to play against.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="3">
<qTxt>What do the boxes in the lobby mean?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Those are different game sessions you can join.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="4">
<qTxt>How do I join a game?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click the Join button to jump into a game session.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="5">
<qTxt>I joined a game. Why isn&apos;t anything happening?</qTxt>
<aTxt>You have to wait until the game session fills up with other players. Then the game will begin.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="6">
<qTxt>Can I leave the game session before the game starts?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Yes. Click on the Leave button to leave the session.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="7">
<qTxt>How do I leave a game session?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click on the Leave button to leave the session.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="8">
<qTxt>Why do I see other players in the boxes?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Those are other players waiting to play the game! Click the Join button to play against them.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="9">
<qTxt>Why did the game session I wanted to join disappear?</qTxt>
<aTxt>As soon as game sessions fill up, they disappear and people start playing the game.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="10">
<qTxt>How do I play against my friend when anyone can join a session?</qTxt>
<aTxt>If you&apos;re waiting to play against someone and a different person joins your session, you&apos;ll have a few seconds to click the Leave button before the game begins.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="11">
<qTxt>My friend started playing a game without me! Can I join that game?</qTxt>
<aTxt>No. Once a game starts, you&apos;ll have to wait for your friend to finish.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
</Subsect><Subsect name="Worm Herder" ssid="2">
<q qid="1">
<qTxt>What is Worm Herder all about?</qTxt>
<aTxt>In this multiplayer Mini Game you have a patch of grass. Your goal is to keep all the worms on your lawn, either by hitting them before they escape, or by pinching them from your opponent&apos;s lawn.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="2">
<qTxt>What are the controls?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Use your mouse to point at the worms. Click on worms that are on your lawn to bonk them. To get worms from your opponent&apos;s lawn, click on a worm and hold the mouse button to pinch it. Drag pinched worms to your lawn and let go of the mouse button to drop them.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="3">
<qTxt>How do I keep worms on my side?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click on escaping worms to bonk them on the head. They&apos;ll get confused and stay on your lawn.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="4">
<qTxt>How do I pinch worms from my opponent?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click and hold the mouse button on an opponent&apos;s worm. Drag the worm to your lawn and let go.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="5">
<qTxt>When does the game end?</qTxt>
<aTxt>The game ends when the timer runs out.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="6">
<qTxt>How do I win?</qTxt>
<aTxt>The person with the most worms when the timer runs out is the winner.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="7">
<qTxt>Which lawn is mine?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Your lawn is indicated at the beginning of the game. It has your player picture over it.  When you point at worms on your lawn, the cursor changes to a wooden mallet.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="8">
<qTxt>Which lawn is my opponent&apos;s?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Your opponent&apos;s lawn is indicated at the beginning of the game.  It has your opponent&apos;s picture over it.  When you point at worms on your opponent&apos;s lawn, the cursor changes to a pair of tweezers.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="9">
<qTxt>What&apos;s a good strategy?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Pinching worms takes longer than bonking worms, so try to bonk as many worms as possible before you start pinching them from your opponent.  If your lawn fills up with escaping worms again, go back to using the mallet.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
</Subsect><Subsect name="Caterthrillar" ssid="3">
<q qid="1">
<qTxt>What is Caterthrillar all about?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Caterthrillar is a fast race to the finish line, with caterpillars instead of cars.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="2">
<qTxt>What are the controls?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Press and hold the UP arrow key on your keyboard to go forward.  Press and hold the LEFT and RIGHT arrow keys to turn.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="3">
<qTxt>How do I know where I&apos;m going?</qTxt>
<aTxt>At the start of the game, your caterpillar will be facing the right direction.  Jut hold the UP arrow key on your keyboard to start moving.  If you go the wrong way, you&apos;ll see a warning.  You can check the track map in the top right corner to see the positions of all caterpillars.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="4">
<qTxt>What happens when I get stuck in a corner?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Hold the UP arrow key on your keyboard and either the LEFT or RIGHT arrow keys.  You caterpillar will slowly squeeze out of the corner.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="5">
<qTxt>Where are the other caterpillars?</qTxt>
<aTxt>The other players look like round coins of different colours.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="6">
<qTxt>How do the other players move so fast?  Are they cheating?</qTxt>
<aTxt>The other player tokens skip around a little.  They&apos;re not cheating - your computer is just getting updates about where the other players are.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="7">
<qTxt>Why does the track look different than the last track I played?</qTxt>
<aTxt>The racetrack is chosen randomly at the start of the game.  There are many different tracks available.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
</Subsect><Subsect name="Fallin' Pollen " ssid="4">
<q qid="1">
<qTxt>What is Fallin&apos; Pollen all about?</qTxt>
<aTxt>You need to keep the pollen from hitting the ground by matching three or more same-coloured pollen spores with your slingshot. The goal is to eliminate all of the spores on the screen. There are two versions of this game on each planet - the one-player (Solo) version and the multiplayer version.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="2">
<qTxt>What are the controls?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Press and hold the LEFT and RIGHT arrow keys on your keyboard to aim your slingshot.  Press the SPACEBAR to fire a pollen spore at the the other pollen spores.  You can bank spores off the walls to get them into tricky spaces. If a spore creates a group of three or more spores with the same colour, those spores will disappear.  Any spores hanging from that group will disappear as well.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="3">
<qTxt>The game is impossible to finish!  Why do I keep getting the same colours?</qTxt>
<aTxt>When you&apos;ve zapped most of the spores, your slingshot will only fire the final few spore colours. Try hanging one colour from another, and zap the top colour.  The clinging spores will disappear with the topmost spores, and you&apos;ll clear the screen.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="4">
<qTxt>Why do my pollen spores bounce back to me?</qTxt>
<aTxt>At some point in the game, the air is filled with hard spores.  Your pollen will bounce right off them.  You can get rid of them by zapping three or more spores that are touching them.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="5">
<qTxt>What is Fallin' Pollen Solo?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Fallin' Pollen Solo is a game you play by yourself. This is a great way to get some practice before challenging another player to the Fallin' Pollen multiplayer version! This is also a way to earn Botanickels if there is no one online you want to play mini games with.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
</Subsect></sect><sect name="Planting" sid="10">
<Subsect name="Planting" ssid="1">
<q qid="1">
<qTxt>What are the brown squares in my garden?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Those are dirt pits. You can plant Seeds in them and grow new Plants.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="2">
<qTxt>Where do I get Seeds from?</qTxt>
<aTxt>You buy Seeds from the Garden shop. You can also get Seeds from Plants you successfully grow to maturity or through trading.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="3">
<qTxt>How do I plant a Seed?</qTxt>
<aTxt>To plant a Seed, go to the garden space in your Pod and click on an empty plot. This will bring up a window showing what Seeds you have. Click on the Seed you want to plant and then click the 'Plant' button. The Seed will then appear in the pit.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="4">
<qTxt>How do Plants grow?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Each Plant has 5 lifespan stages. If you take good care of your Seed it will sprout, turn into a stem, grow leaves and then reach maturity. Once it reaches maturity, it will drop Seeds. Just like in real life, if you don't take care of your Plant, it will die.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="5">
<qTxt>How do I check to see how my Plant is doing?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click on a plant to bring up its information window. This window shows what the plant currently looks like, what lifespan stage it is in, and its health. You can see how your plant is doing by the Health bar - if the bar is getting low, you should care for your Plant or it might die.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="6">
<qTxt>How do I care for my Plant?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click on the Plant you want to care for and then click on the 'Care' button. This will launch the Tuber Shooter game. Depending on how well you do in this game will determine how much health your Plant gains.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="7">
<qTxt>How do I play Tuber Shooter?</qTxt>
<aTxt>The objective in Tuber Shooter is to shoot the bugs and suck in water droplets. Use your mouse to rotate and click the mouse button to shoot. Depending on how well you do, you will earn health points for your Plant.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="8">
<qTxt>My Plant grew all of a sudden!  What's going on?</qTxt>
<aTxt>A plant will keep growing whether you care for it or not. Your Plant just entered the next stage of growth.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="9">
<qTxt>My Plant is sparkling - what does that mean?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Congrats! That means your Plant has reached maturity and has dropped Seeds. Click on the Plant and then click 'Collect Seeds'.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="10">
<qTxt>What happens when my Plant reaches maturity?</qTxt>
<aTxt>When a Plant reaches maturity (becomes full-grown), it will drop Seeds which you can either re-plant, sell to the Garden shop or trade. If you help your Plant reach maturity by caring for it, you will also earn Experience Points (XP). You must click on your Plant in order to get the XP.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="11">
<qTxt>My Plant is all brown and withered. What happened?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Your Plant has moved on to that Great Greenhouse in the Sky!  Dead plants take up room in your garden, and they look pretty ugly, so you should pull them.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="12">
<qTxt>Why did my Plant die?</qTxt>
<aTxt>If you don&apos;t take good care of your Plant (i.e. if its Health meter reaches zero), it will die. If you have a dead Plant in your garden, just pull it out.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="13">
<qTxt>How do I remove a Plant from my garden?</qTxt>
<aTxt>If you no longer want a Plant in your garden or if you have a dead Plant, you can remove it by pulling it out. Click on the Plant you want to remove and then choose the 'Pull' option. Your Plant will be removed from the pit, making room for a new Plant.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="14">
<qTxt>How do I know which Seeds to plant?</qTxt>
<aTxt>You can plant whatever Seeds you'd like - it is your garden after all! When looking at a Seed in the Garden shop or in your inventory, you can see what attributes it has by putting your mouse cursor over it. The attributes include the Plant's name, its level, growth rate and how many leaves and flowers it will have when matured. It will also show an image of how the Plant will look when full-grown. This info can come in handy when decided what two Seeds to combine as the Plants you create will take attributes from both Seeds.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="15">
<qTxt>How do I combine Seeds?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Level 10 gardeners have the ability to combine two Seeds in one pit. By combining Seeds, you can create a Graft, which is Plant that takes attributes from both Seeds. This is a great way to grow unique Plants!</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="16">
<qTxt>How do I use Gizmos?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Gizmos are special tools you use when gardening. They can do things like improve your Plant&apos;s health or alter its colour. To use a Gizmo, you must first click on a Plant. Then click on the Gizmo you want to use. You can only use a Gizmo in your inventory once, use it wisely.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="17">
<qTxt>Where can I sell Seeds?</qTxt>
<aTxt>You can sell the Seeds that are dropped by mature Plants to the Garden shop. The amount of Botanickels you will get for a Seed will depend on how valuable it is.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="18">
<qTxt>What determines how valuable a Seed is?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Seeds that have unique properties or are not as common are worth more Botanickels when you sell them.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="19">
<qTxt>How do I get more planting pits?</qTxt>
<aTxt>You can&apos;t. All Pods are limited to five planting pits.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
</Subsect></sect><sect name="Membership" sid="11">
<Subsect name="Membership" ssid="1">
<q qid="1">
<qTxt>What are the benefits of becoming a member?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Membership is free! With a membership, you can play any of the games on The Big Rip, receive The Big Rip Newsletter to find out the latest news on your favourite games, and participate on The Big Rip Message Boards.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="2">
<qTxt>Why do I need to become a member to play?</qTxt>
<aTxt>GalaXseeds (and the other games on The Big Rip) are multi-player games where you create a character to play with. In order to be able to always play with that character (as well as keep track of all your profile info, inventory items and number of Botanickels) the game needs to be able to know who you are. That's why you need to register for an account!  You only need to make 1 account on The Big Rip site - and you use the same account to log into each game.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="3">
<qTxt>How do I become a member?</qTxt>
<aTxt>To become a member, click on the &apos;Sign Up&apos; link at the top of the page or follow this link and enter in the appropriate information. When your membership is enabled, you will be sent an email. You will be asked to confirm your email address at that time. Once confirmed, your membership will be active.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="4">
<qTxt>What if I share an email address with another member of my household?</qTxt>
<aTxt>For security purposes, we can&apos;t allow the same email address to be used for different membership accounts. If there is no second email address available, we suggest contacting your Internet Service Provider. Most ISPs allow you to have more than one address at no extra charge. Failing that, we suggest signing up for a free web-based email address.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="5">
<qTxt>How do I pick a username?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Because we have thousands of users, choosing a name can be tricky. We suggest creating a nickname based on words or things you like. Please don't use your real name in your username - if you do, your account will not be approved.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="6">
<qTxt>Why do I need to give some personal info to sign up, and how&apos;s it being used?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Any personally identifiable information collected from our members is for The Big Rip purposes only (e.g. membership verification, contest fulfillment, etc.). We will never sell or give any of this information to third parties. Sometimes we may share aggregated information, however specific members are never identified. Please read our privacy policy for more details.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="7">
<qTxt>I forgot my username/password. How can I get that info?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Click the &apos;forgot username/password&apos; link on the login page.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="8">
<qTxt>How do I change my username?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Unfortunately, you cannot change your username. You would have to delete your account and start again.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="9">
<qTxt>How do I change my password?</qTxt>
<aTxt>When you&apos;re logged in, click on your username at the top of the page; you will be able to make the changes there.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="10">
<qTxt>Is Membership free?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Yes, Membership is completely free.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="11">
<qTxt>Does my YTV.com account work on The Big Rip?</qTxt>
<aTxt>Yes it does! If you are a member of YTV.com, you can use your username/password to log into any of The Big Rip games!</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="12">
<qTxt>Why can&apos;t I log in?</qTxt>
<aTxt>some more information, such as what browser you&apos;re using (Internet Explorer, Firefox, etc.) or any error messages you see when you try to sign in.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="13">
<qTxt>I changed my email address. How do I update my membership?</qTxt>
<aTxt>If you want to change your email address, all you have to do is log in to your account. Once logged in, click on your username at the top of the page. You&apos;ll find the area where you can change your email address there; you can even use that section to change your password.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="14">
<qTxt>How do I cancel my membership?</qTxt>
<aTxt>If you wish to cancel you membership, please email us letting us know. Your email MUST be from the same email address listed in your account profile - that is how we know it is really you!</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="15">
<qTxt>How do I subscribe or unsubscribe to The Big Rip Newsletter?</qTxt>
<aTxt>In order to subscribe or unsubscribe to The Big Rip Newsletter, you must log in and go to &apos;My Account&apos;.  You can choose to opt-in or out of the newsletter there.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
</Subsect></sect><sect name="Troubleshooting" sid="12">
<Subsect name="Troubleshooting" ssid="1">
<q qid="1">
<qTxt>Why can&apos;t see everything properly on GalaXseeds.com?</qTxt>
<aTxt>If you&apos;re not seeing the entire Site properly, you may need to download Flash 8.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="2">
<qTxt>What is The Big Rip?</qTxt>
<aTxt>The Big Rip is the name of the site where you can find multiplayer online games (GalaXseeds is one of the games).  In order to play any of the games, you need to sign up for a membership account. You can log into any of The Big Rip games with the one account.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="3">
<qTxt>How do I subscribe to the The Big Rip Newsletter?</qTxt>
<aTxt>You can subscribe to the The Big Rip newsletter by becoming a member on any of our game websites. If you&apos;re already a member, you can edit your profile page to request the The Big Rip newsletter. To do this, log in and click your username at the top of the page.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
<q qid="4">
<qTxt>How do I unsubscribe from The Big Rip newsletter?</qTxt>
<aTxt>If you would not like to receive The Big Rip newsletter anymore, just follow the unsubscribe info that is at the bottom of each newsletter.</aTxt>
<img></img>
</q>
</Subsect></sect>
</help>